# DANIEL BENNETT

### Contact

615-785-2922

danielbradleybennett@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/danielbradleybennett Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/danielbbennett

### **PROJECTS**

## The Tavern: Front End Capstone

React/CSS/Bootstrap/external API/dbdiagram
Created an app that allows new and veteran
tabletop role-playing gamers to search an
external API for D&D 5th edition related
content and to create and save their own
content to a local API.

- Users can register and log into their own unique account
- Users can search an external API for D&D
   5th edition related content
- Users can create and save content for their games
- Users can create and save session and world building notes
- Users can edit and delete all user generated data within the app

#### Nutshell

Worked with 4 other individuals to create a dashboard that allows the user to register and log into a unique account, send messages, add news, events, tasks, and friends using React to implement full CRUD.

### **Holiday Road**

Worked with 3 other individuals to create an itinerary geared toward a particular client using a 3rd party API allowing the user to search parks, eateries, and destinations and to create and save an itinerary to a local JSON database.

Back End Capstone

# ABOUT

I have spent most my life pursuing vocational ministry. Though I will always love my vocational work, economically the positions I were working could not meet basic economic needs. I became a jack of all trades to subsidize my income while continuing to work with my ministry. Physical wear and tear on my body, provoked me to look into other avenues of employment. In my search, I began to notice a huge need for technology jobs in Nashville. After doing some research, I applied to Nashville Software School. Since I had no technical experience, they recommended me to take a six week Jump Start Class. I signed up and in May 2019 and I wrote my first line of code. I was intrigued, fascinated, and knew I wanted to learn more. I like that development allows me to continuously learn and be challenged. The more I dive into development excited I am to begin my career as a Software Developer.

## EXPERIENCE

- Utilize third party Api's to render data to a website application
- Create an API to store and render user data
- Create a single page application using Javascript, CSS, HTML and React
- Manage Github flow through individual and group projects
- Create a CRUD application during individual and group projects using a JSON-Server

## EDUCATION

Nashville Software School Nashville, TN Certificate in Software Development, 2020

Visible Music College; Memphis, TN BM Modern Worship Leading, 2011

Middle Tennessee State University; Murfreesboro, TN BS Liberal Studies, 2003

# **Work Experience**

### Vaco, Franklin, TN

Data Entry Assistant, 2019

- Contracted through Vaco to work at SESAC
- Complete all assigned Data Entry requests within required timeframe while maintaining a high level of quality

### Glass Creek Apartments, Mt Juliet, TN

Groundskeeper, 2018-2019

• Maintained appearance of property by disposing of trash, cleaning breezeways, and pressure washing buildings

## Skyline Exhibitor Source, Lavergne, TN

Service Technician, 2016-2018

- Collaborate with team to install and dismantle exhibits for events and trade shows
- Sort and inspect client owned items going to and returning from a show

# Hobby Lobby, Murfreesboro, TN

Associate, 2016

- Received and unloaded deliveries, organized inventory in storage areas, and stocked store shelves with products.
- Located items for customers and maintained store cleanliness.

## Forge Youth Center, Englewood, CO

Student Ministry Leader, 2015-2016

- Instrumental in creating an after-school program for underserved teenagers from the ground up
- Facilitated various after-school activities
- Led events and programs

### Visible Music College, Memphis, TN

Student Life Manager, 2011-2015

- Assisted Vice President of Students in various executive tasks
- Oversaw multiple facilities, including inspections and distribution of equipment.
- Organized student housing assignments for each semester
- Developed weekly student and housing reports for Vice President of Students
- Available to students and stakeholders for emergencies and crises maintaining discretion as needed
- Served on multiple evaluation teams
- Contributed to the development of the Student Handbook and the Housing Policy and Procedures

### Belle Aire Baptist Church, Murfreesboro, TN

Facilities Team, 2001-2008

- Managed facility maintenance for church with over 2,000 members
- Coordinated use of facility for church events including worship services, meals, community events, weddings, etc.